<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Alexandre Nuttinck</title><link>https://alexnuttinck.dev/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Alexandre Nuttinck</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alexnuttinck.dev/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Day Sysadmins Quit</title><link>https://alexnuttinck.dev/posts/5-the-day-sysadmins-quit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://alexnuttinck.dev/posts/5-the-day-sysadmins-quit/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://alexnuttinck.dev/posts/adventures-in-uptime/5-the-day-sysadmins-quit.png"
alt="Adventures in Uptime - The Day Sysadmins Quit"
&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This story is inspired by something very real: the invisible work of system administrators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their job isn’t to ship new features or flashy updates, it’s to make sure that everything just works.
Servers stay up, backups run, emails flow, and systems stay secure.
Most of it happens quietly, behind the scenes, where no one really notices&amp;hellip; until something breaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, some managers don’t see that.
When they don’t understand the technical side, they think &amp;ldquo;nothing’s happening.&amp;rdquo;
Micromanagement takes over, trust disappears, and appreciation fades.
And eventually, the sysadmins decide to leave. Because, let’s be honest, there’s no shortage of work for skilled people elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Million-Dollar Mistake</title><link>https://alexnuttinck.dev/posts/4-the-million-dollar-mistake/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://alexnuttinck.dev/posts/4-the-million-dollar-mistake/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://alexnuttinck.dev/posts/adventures-in-uptime/4-the-million-dollar-mistake.png"
alt="Adventures in Uptime - The Million-Dollar Mistake"
&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A major project had just been approved: a collaboration between several partners, with a generous budget to set up new infrastructure.
One partner was in charge of purchasing the servers and hosting them in their datacenter.
The plan was simple: coordinate with everyone, agree on the specifications, and move forward together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well&amp;hellip; that last part didn’t happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without consulting anyone, the partner decided to order high-end IBM proprietary Big Data servers, proudly announcing the purchase once it was too late to change anything. 💸&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Blue Screen of Container Death</title><link>https://alexnuttinck.dev/posts/3-the-blue-screen-of-container-death/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://alexnuttinck.dev/posts/3-the-blue-screen-of-container-death/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://alexnuttinck.dev/posts/adventures-in-uptime/3-the-blue-screen-of-container-death.png"
alt="Adventures in Uptime - The Blue Screen of Container Death"
&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It started as a new and exciting mission.
The client needed help setting up proper CI/CD pipelines and introducing DevOps best practices. Everything sounded great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then came the small detail that hadn’t been mentioned during the initial discussions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Oh, by the way, our application runs on Windows… and we use Windows containers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I froze for a second.
Windows… containers? I didn’t even know those existed before that project.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cloud Loops</title><link>https://alexnuttinck.dev/posts/2-cloud-loops/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://alexnuttinck.dev/posts/2-cloud-loops/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://alexnuttinck.dev/posts/adventures-in-uptime/2-cloud-loops.png"
alt="Adventures in Uptime - Cloud Loops"
&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It happened during a mission for a client.
They had decided to move everything to AWS, hoping to scale faster and more easily than with their old bare-metal self-hosted infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, everything looked perfect. Deployments were smoother, scaling was instant, and everyone was proud of how modern it all felt.
The promise of “infinite scalability” seemed within reach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then, the invoices started growing.
Each month, the costs climbed higher, and every time the cluster expanded, the bill followed.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Reproducibility Crisis</title><link>https://alexnuttinck.dev/posts/1-the-reproducibility-crisis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://alexnuttinck.dev/posts/1-the-reproducibility-crisis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This one goes back to one of my very first missions.
I arrived at the client’s office, full of energy, ready to dive into their development environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I asked the classic first question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Can I get access to the dev environment?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer? A USB key.
Inside it, a virtual machine image, several gigabytes of it, along with a Word document as the only piece of documentation for the setup. No Git repository, no configuration management, &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Adventures in Uptime</title><link>https://alexnuttinck.dev/posts/adventures-in-uptime/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://alexnuttinck.dev/posts/adventures-in-uptime/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Adventures in Uptime is a comic series born from real-life stories I’ve experienced during my years working in IT as a sysadmin and DevOps engineer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a humorous take on the sometimes absurd, always unpredictable world of technology, where coffee machines crash, servers live under desks, and “everything is a priority.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to capture those everyday anecdotes we all laugh about later. The kind of moments that every engineer, sysadmin, or office worker has lived at least once.
So I decided to turn them into comics.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>